Register of the Anatole S. Loukashkin Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- PRINTED MATTER, 1901-1978
  - Newspaper issues.
    - Natsiia: Ezhenedel'nyi organ Rossiiskago fashistskago soiuza, Harbin, incomplete issue #22, #14, #26, (1 August 1939) (31 March 1940) (7 July 1940) (Folder 30: 4)
    - Novaia zhizn'.
    - Novoe russkoe slovo, New York, and, 1947 n.d. (Folder 30: 5)
      Clippings
    - Novoe vremia, Shanghai, 1942-1945
    - Novosti dnia, Shanghai.
    - Novosti dnia, Tientsin.
    - Novosti zhizni.
    - Novyi put', Shanghai, #82, #57, (28 July 1935) (1 January 1936) (Folder 30: 6)
    - Pamiati doktora V. A. Kazem-Beka: Odnodnevnaia gazeta, izdavaemaia v godovshchinu ego konchiny, Harbin, 4 August 1934 (Folder 30: 7)
    - Pravoslavnaia Rus', Czechoslovakia?, #12, (25 June 1935 (O.S.) (Folder 30: 8)
    - Rossiia, New York, Vol. XXX, #4384, #7475., (19 May 1950) (24 November 1962) (Folder 30: 9)
      Includes clippings
    - Rozhdestvenskaia gazeta Kharbinskago Komiteta Pomoshchi Russkim Biezhentsam, Harbin, 7 January 1931 (Folder 30: 10)
    - Russkaia gazeta v Parizhie, Paris, #1, #130, (7 January 1924) (25 September 1924) (Folder 30: 11)
    - Russkaia mysl', San Francisco, #13 (21 May?), #20, (19 May 1928) (Folder 30: 12)
    - Russkii ezhenedel'nik v Bel'gii, Bruxelles, #413-284, #419-290, #436-307, #451, #453-324, #457-328, (4 October 1935) (15 November 1935) (13 March 1936) (26 June 1936) (10 July 1936) (14 August 1936) (Folder 30: 13)
    - Russkii invalid, Harbin, 22 May 1945 (Folder 30: 14)
    - Russkoe dielo: Odnodnevnaia gazeta Kharbinskago Komiteta Pomoshchi Russkim Biezhentsam, Harbin, #2, (7 April 1932) (Folder 30: 15)
    - Russkoe slovo, Harbin, #1, (1 January 1956) (Folder 30: 16)
    - Russkoe vremia, Shanghai, one incomplete issue, and one clipping, 21 October 1941 (Folder 30: 17)
    - Shankhaiskaia zaria, Shanghai, incomplete # 4532, incomplete #4708, #6024., (3 July 1939) (27 December 1939) (9 September 1943) (Folder 30: 18)
    - Slovo, San Francisco, #1-15, (June-September 1967) (Folder 30: 19)
    - Slovo, Shanghai.
    - Soobshcheniia natsional'nogo predstavitel'stva Rossiiskoi emigratsii v Germanskoi Federal'noi Respublike (NATsPRE), München, #13, (November 1956) (Folder 30: 20)
    - Vecherniaia zaria, Shanghai, three incomplete issues, and, and clippings, 1942 1945 (Folder 30: 21)
    - Viestnik, Tientsin, one incomplete issue #2, (7 May 1927) (Folder 30: 22)
    - Vozrozhdenie Azii.
    - Za vozvrashchenie na Rodinu, Berlin, #46, (September 1956) (Folder 30: 23)
    - Zria(?), #1 (Folder 30: 24)
    - Unidentified (Folder 30: 25)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1908-1974 (Box 31)
  - Chinese-language document (Folder 31: 1)
  - Clippings (Folder 31: 2)
  - Newspaper issues
    - Kitaisko-russkaia gazeta, Shanghai, #515, (21 January 1949) (Folder 31: 3)
    - Novaia zhizn', Shanghai, #1472, #1474, #2372, #2553, #2723., (9 May 1945) (10 May 1945-special edition) (11 November 1947) (11 May 1948) (28 October 1948) (Folder 31: 4)
    - Novoe vremia, Shanghai, 1942-1945 (Folder 31: 5)
      Clippings and incomplete issues
    - Novosti dnia, Shanghai, # 343, #39., (19 December 1946) (11 February 1947) (Folder 31: 6)
    - Novosti dnia, Tientsin, #185, #121., (9 November 1945) (3 September 1946) (Folder 31: 7)
    - Novosti zhizni, Harbin, #202-204, #206, #212-213, #215, #220-229, #61, (3-5 October 1918) (8 October 1918) (16-17 October 1918) (19 October 1918) (25 October-6 November 1918) (23 March 1919) (Folder 31: 8)
    - Slovo, Shanghai, #3971, #4335, #4441., (10 April 1940) (16 April 1941) (3 August 1941) (Folder 31: 9)
    - Vozrozhdenie Azii, Tientsin, #897, #3080., (16 January 1936) (21 April 1942) (Folder 31: 10)
      Includes incomplete issues and clippings, 1937-1944
  - Scrapbooks (Box 32)
    - Displaced persons. (Folder 32: 1)
      Clippings, correspondence and other printed matter relating to and produced by Russian displaced persons in Europe, 1940s-1950s
    - Russkaia Pravoslavnaia Tserkov'. (Folder 32: 2)
      Clippings, photographs, writings and other printed matter depicting aspects of church life in Russia and abroad
    - Russkaia zhizn'. (Folder 32: 3)
      Commemorative addresses, letters of thanks, photographs and other materials
    - Soviet Union--History-- 1925-1953. (Folder 32: 4)
      Primarily clippings on state-sponsored repression
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1903-1972 (Box 33)
  - Albums
    - Two albums with prints depicting the construction of the Khukhai Railway (Manchuria) (Folder 33: 1-2)
    - One album depicting events and people associated with the newspaper Russkaia zhizn' (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Loose prints and negatives
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Five prints and one photostatic reproduction of Eisenhower alone and in groups, including one with Loukashkin (Folder 34: 2)
    - Marly, Anna. (Folder 34: 3)
      Two prints
    - Russian Boy Scouts, Manchuria. (Folder 34: 4)
      Three prints and three negatives
    - Russian Center. (Folder 34: 5)
    - Russkaia Pravoslavnaia Tserkov'. (Folder 34: 6)
      Twenty prints depicting Church prelates and cathedrals, especially in San Francisco
    - Russkaia Zhizn'. (Folder 34: 7)
      Thirteen prints depicting editors and authors associated with this newspaper
    - Sarov, Russia.
      Four prints of Sarov and the Sarov monastery dating from 1903-1904
    - Serebrennikov, I. I. and Serebrennikova, A. N. (Folder 34: 8)
      Three prints
    - 22 nd Invalids' Ball. (Folder 34: 9)
      Ten prints
    - Miscellany. (Folder 34: 10)
      Seven prints and one negative of unidentified groups of people, things, and places